<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Makrand Khanwale</title>
    <link>https://makrandak.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Makrand Khanwale</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://makrandak.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://makrandak.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://makrandak.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>You can reach me by email at:
makrand dot khanwale at tum dot de
Office address (Beginning May 2026):
Technische Universität München
Boltzmannstraße 15
85747 Garching bei München
Germany</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An efficient semi-implicit block second order solver for simulating two-phase flows</title>
      <link>https://makrandak.github.io/research_updates/projection-block-solver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://makrandak.github.io/research_updates/projection-block-solver/</guid>
      <description>In picture above: Progressive zoomed in mesh for Rayleigh Taylor instability in the chaotic turbulent regime for the density ratio of 1:10.
Summary In this work we present a projection-based framework for solving a thermodynamically-consistent Cahn-Hilliard Navier-Stokes system that models two-phase flows. In this work we extend the fully implicit method presented in Khanwale et al. [A fully-coupled framework for solving Cahn-Hilliard Navier-Stokes equa- tions: Second-order, energy-stable numerical methods on adaptive octree based meshes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://makrandak.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://makrandak.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>In-peer reviewed journals Star * denotes equal contribution
2026
 Kumar Saurabh, Makrand A. Khanwale, Masado Ishii, Hari Sundar, and Baskar Ganapathysubramanian. “Field conserving adaptive mesh refinement (AMR) scheme on massively parallel adaptive octree meshes”. arXiv preprint arXiv:2602.07817 (2026). [ARXIV]  2025
 Reed L Brown, Shahab Mirjalili, Makrand A. Khanwale, and Ali Mani. “A mass-conserving contact line treatment for second-order conservative phase field methods based on the generalized Navier boundary condition”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An adaptive block solver for simulating two-phase flows</title>
      <link>https://makrandak.github.io/research_updates/block-solver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://makrandak.github.io/research_updates/block-solver/</guid>
      <description>In picture above: Comparison of bubble shapes and terminal velocities with experimental results and corresponding streamlines.
Summary In our recent work on block-solver for simulating two-phase flows with deforming interfaces at various density contrasts by solving thermodynamically consistent Cahn-Hilliard Navier-Stokes equations. We use fully implicit non-linear finite element based methods.
 Highlights of the work   Two-phase flows simulated using thermodynamically consistent Cahn-Hilliard Navier-Stokes equations.
  Provably energy-stable Crank-Nicolson-type time integration scheme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An adaptive fully-coupled second order solver for simulating two-phase flows</title>
      <link>https://makrandak.github.io/research_updates/fully-coupled-solver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://makrandak.github.io/research_updates/fully-coupled-solver/</guid>
      <description>In picture above: Progression of 2D Rayleigh-Taylor instability to chaotic turbulent regime for the density ratio of 1:10.
Summary In our recent work on fully coupled solver for simulating two-phase flows by solving thermodynamically consistent Cahn-Hilliard Navier-Stokes equations (CHNS). We use fully implicit non-linear finite element based methods. The fully coupled approach solves CHNS equations in one full block minimizing the number of matrix assemblies compared to the block approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>https://makrandak.github.io/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://makrandak.github.io/experience/</guid>
      <description>Research Appointments Department of Mechanical Engineering, Stanford University, California, USA Physical Science Research Scientist
September 2024 – Present
Supervisor: Prof. Ali Mani
 Develop Reynolds-stress-based turbulence closure models using high-fidelity direct numerical simulations. Develop computational frameworks for modeling compressible multiphase flows for the INSIEME project under the PSAAP-III program. Design scalable numerical methods and simulation tools for multiphysics flow systems on modern high-performance computing architectures.  Center for Turbulence Research, Department of Mechanical Engineering, Stanford University, California, USA CTR Postdoctoral Research Fellow</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://makrandak.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://makrandak.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>My research focuses on developing computational frameworks for multiphysics fluid dynamics, combining rigorous numerical analysis, high-fidelity simulation, and high-performance computing. This work bridges physics, applied mathematics, and computer science to enable predictive modeling of complex fluid dynamical systems. Building on this foundation, our research group develops computational tools to study multiphysics transport phenomena relevant to energy systems, aerospace applications, sustainable transport, hydrogen production, and environmental flows.
 .lb-figure { max-width: 900px; margin: 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>