<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Makrand Khanwale</title>
    <link>https://makrandak.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Makrand Khanwale</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://makrandak.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An adaptive block solver for simulating two-phase flows</title>
      <link>https://makrandak.github.io/research_updates/block-solver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://makrandak.github.io/research_updates/block-solver/</guid>
      <description>In picture above: Comparison of bubble shapes and terminal velocities with experimental results and corresponding streamlines.
Summary In our recent work on block-solver for simulating two-phase flows with deforming interfaces at various density contrasts by solving thermodynamically consistent Cahn-Hilliard Navier-Stokes equations. We use fully implicit non-linear finite element based methods.
 Highlights of the work   Two-phase flows simulated using thermodynamically consistent Cahn-Hilliard Navier-Stokes equations.
  Provably energy-stable Crank-Nicolson-type time integration scheme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An adaptive fully-coupled second order solver for simulating two-phase flows</title>
      <link>https://makrandak.github.io/research_updates/fully-coupled-solver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://makrandak.github.io/research_updates/fully-coupled-solver/</guid>
      <description>In picture above: Progression of 2D Rayleigh-Taylor instability to chaotic turbulent regime for the density ratio of 1:10.
Summary In our recent work on fully coupled solver for simulating two-phase flows by solving thermodynamically consistent Cahn-Hilliard Navier-Stokes equations (CHNS). We use fully implicit non-linear finite element based methods. The fully coupled approach solves CHNS equations in one full block minimizing the number of matrix assemblies compared to the block approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://makrandak.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://makrandak.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>In-peer reviewed journals 2021
 Makrand A. Khanwale, Kumar Saurabh, Masado Ishii, Hari Sundar, and James A. Rossmanith. &amp;ldquo;A projection-based, semi-implicit time-stepping approach for the Cahn-Hilliard Navier-Stokes equations on adaptive octree meshes.&amp;rdquo; In: Submitted to Journal of Computational Physics : arXiv preprint arXiv:2107.05123 (2021). [ARXIV]  2020
  Kumar Saurabh, Boshun Gao, Milinda Fernando, Songzhe Xu, Biswajit Khara, Makrand A. Khanwale, Ming-Chen Hsu, Adarsh Krishnamurthy, Hari Sundar, and Baskar Ganapathysubramanian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://makrandak.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://makrandak.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I currently am a Postdoctoral Fellow at Center for Turbulence Research, Stanford University, where I work with Prof. Ali Mani. I recieved my PhD at Iowa State University co-majoring in Mechanical engineering and Applied Mathematics. I was co-advised by Dr. Baskar Ganapathysubramanian and Dr. James Rossmanith. I work on development and analysis of numerical schemes for high fidelity simulations of fluid flows. As a part of my PhD, I developed energy stable numerical methods to simulate two-phase flows using Cahn-Hilliard Navier-Stokes equations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>https://makrandak.github.io/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://makrandak.github.io/experience/</guid>
      <description>Research Experience: Center for Turbulence Research, Department of Mechanical Engineering, Stanford University, CA  Postdoctoral Fellow [Aug 2021 - Ongoing]
Project supervisors: Prof. Ali Mani  Department of Mechanical Engineering and Department of Mathematics, Iowa State University, Ames, Iowa  Graduate Research/Teaching Assistant [Aug 2016 – Aug 2021]
Project supervisors: Prof. Baskar Ganapathysubramanian and Prof. James Rossmanith
Title: Energy-Stable Finite Element Methods for the Simulation of Two-Phase flows using Cahn-Hilliard Navier-Stokes Equations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://makrandak.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://makrandak.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>