<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research_updates on Makrand Khanwale</title>
    <link>https://makrandak.github.io/research_updates/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research_updates on Makrand Khanwale</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://makrandak.github.io/research_updates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An efficient semi-implicit block second order solver for simulating two-phase flows</title>
      <link>https://makrandak.github.io/research_updates/projection-block-solver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://makrandak.github.io/research_updates/projection-block-solver/</guid>
      <description>In picture above: Progressive zoomed in mesh for Rayleigh Taylor instability in the chaotic turbulent regime for the density ratio of 1:10.
Summary In this work we present a projection-based framework for solving a thermodynamically-consistent Cahn-Hilliard Navier-Stokes system that models two-phase flows. In this work we extend the fully implicit method presented in Khanwale et al. [A fully-coupled framework for solving Cahn-Hilliard Navier-Stokes equa- tions: Second-order, energy-stable numerical methods on adaptive octree based meshes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An adaptive block solver for simulating two-phase flows</title>
      <link>https://makrandak.github.io/research_updates/block-solver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://makrandak.github.io/research_updates/block-solver/</guid>
      <description>In picture above: Comparison of bubble shapes and terminal velocities with experimental results and corresponding streamlines.
Summary In our recent work on block-solver for simulating two-phase flows with deforming interfaces at various density contrasts by solving thermodynamically consistent Cahn-Hilliard Navier-Stokes equations. We use fully implicit non-linear finite element based methods.
 Highlights of the work   Two-phase flows simulated using thermodynamically consistent Cahn-Hilliard Navier-Stokes equations.
  Provably energy-stable Crank-Nicolson-type time integration scheme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An adaptive fully-coupled second order solver for simulating two-phase flows</title>
      <link>https://makrandak.github.io/research_updates/fully-coupled-solver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://makrandak.github.io/research_updates/fully-coupled-solver/</guid>
      <description>In picture above: Progression of 2D Rayleigh-Taylor instability to chaotic turbulent regime for the density ratio of 1:10.
Summary In our recent work on fully coupled solver for simulating two-phase flows by solving thermodynamically consistent Cahn-Hilliard Navier-Stokes equations (CHNS). We use fully implicit non-linear finite element based methods. The fully coupled approach solves CHNS equations in one full block minimizing the number of matrix assemblies compared to the block approach.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>